# **Edward Cloud**

Portland, Indiana **502-424-3999** 

EdwardLCloud@gmail.com https://github.com/cloudedl/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardcloudonline/

For the last 8 years in IT as an advisor have helped thousands of people find software and hardware solutions. Now I apply that technical problem solving experience to the world of software engineering with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, MondoDB, Python, SQL, and Django. I bring a culture of innovation and fresh perspective.

# **Experience**

February 2022 - May 2022

# General Assembly, Remote

- Utilized Github to work with class materials and projects
- Experience working solo and in a group setting
- Created and deployed working sites that utilized HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, MondoDB, Python, SQL, and Django
- Created API's and utilized 3rd party API's
- Experience with both class based and hook based React

July 2015 - February 2022

### Apple, Remote

June 2021 - February 2022

#### **Apple Online Store CE**

- Work with Github, Git, Redhat Linux, Nginx, Docker to help modify and deploy apple.com architecture in the dev environment
- Train in new skill sets such as Python, Nginx, AWS, Git, RedHat

December 2017 - June 2021

### **Senior Advisor**

- Global Support working across multiple platforms such as IOS, MacOS, Windows, iTunes
- Achieved Top 3% and ACEA award
- Handled requests to speak to manager and appearement requests
- Experience with GBI Portal, Northstar, SafeView, Commitments Tracker, Central Station, Quip, Box, Slack, GSX
- Using PAIR and other Troubleshooting processes to quickly isolate the issue
- Lead Presentations in my Team Meetings
- Coached and provided to support to our TeamX Retail Group during COVID-19

November 2019 - July 2020

### ApplePay OverFlow Advisor

- Volunteered to take optional queue to help my peers
- Proficient in directing customer to Green Dot Bank, Goldman Sachs, Customer's
  Financial Institution, or Apple Media Services as needed
- Educate customer on how Apple Pay Works and the different ways to use it

November 2018 - March 2019

#### Commitments Team Rotational Advisor

- Utilized a complex Excel Tracker working through intricate multi-page formulas
- Worked independently requiring excellent time management ensuring commitments were kept on time
- Participated in an Ownership Pilot program that involved tracking and improving of a unique tracker separate from the usual role
- Worked in Almost every Specialization available including VM Admin, Tracker Checker, Mentor, APSS Tracker, Sweep Counter
- Experience with OPUS and Apple Manage

July 2014 - July 2015

### Staples, Muncie Indiana

### **East Tech Representative**

- Triaged Customer devices as they entered the tech bench.
- Completed Hardware Repairs on Customer Devices
- Resolved Software and Virus related issues
- Setup Wireless networks and printers onsite at customer locations.

# Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, MongoDB, Python, Django, SQL, Debian Linux, Fedora Linux, MacOS,

# **Projects**

https://cloudedl.github.io/Wizards-Quest/ - 1st project, Javascript Game

https://shoporium.herokuapp.com/ - 2nd project MEN Stack Shop App

https://go-nutri-cart.herokuapp.com/ - 3rd project MERN Stack Shop app

https://tempo-math.herokuapp.com/ -4th project DJANGO Teaching App

# **Education**

Ivy Tech Community College Sellersburg, Indiana

A.S. in Computer Information Technology (PC Hardware and Software, Linux, Networking, Active Directory, Basic Programming) A+ Certification (Expired)